Hello everyone, I am thinking of
taking health insurance from Ajith Dito Insurance
but am
confused by the many plans and options. So
now let's
compare the top three policies in the market to give you clarity
.  Aditya Birla Active One Max
HDFC Argo Optima Secure and Care
Supreme Watch this video in full.  You will know which of these three
plans suits you best
.  So let's get
started.  First,
a brief overview of the company's performance.
HCA Ergo's claim settlement
ratio has
been 98% on average for the last three years.  This means that out of every 100
claims, 98 claims are settled
.  In addition, the number of complaints is also
very low, with only seven complaints
per 10,000 claims, and the unclaimed
claim ratio is also 86%.  This means that out of
every 100 premiums collected,
they are using ₹86 for claim settlements
.  And network hospitals are
also very robust with over ₹13,000
plus network hospitals across
India.  So overall, Gahef Ergo
has a super strong track record.  Now coming
to Aditya Birla Aditya Birla's average
claim settlement ratio
is 95% for the last three years.
Complaints are also low. Overall, we have
22 complaints but 10,000 claims
registered.
If we look at the average income claim ratio for the last three years, we have 68%.  So that means
68 out of every 100 are
using it for claim settlements
.  And there are
also 12,000 plus network hospitals across India
.  So comparatively,
Aditya Birla is a new player among these three companies, but its
performance is still impressive
.  If we look at Now Care Health Insurance,
we have been maintaining a
90% claim settlement ratio for the last three years. On average, there
are around 11,400 plus network hospitals across the country, but the
complaints are comparatively a bit higher
.  So 36 complaints per 10,000
claims and the unclaimed claim ratio
is also solid at 59%, meaning they are
maintaining profitability and
also settling claims
.  So overall, HDFC Ergo is in the lead in brand
strength, post-sale services and
customer experience
.  Now coming to the plans, let's
first look at HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure. The highlight of this plan is the
Secure Benefit, which means that
our cover amount will double from day one.  For
example, if I take a 10-lock policy,
I will be
provided with 20-lock coverage from day one
.  And besides that, we have
no restrictions in this policy.   There are
no room rent restrictions,
no co-payments, and no
restrictions like disease-related supplements
.  So 100% of the medical expenses will be
settled by the insurance company.
And along with that, we are also covered for all the basic features
.  For example,
modern treatments, AYUSH
benefits and domiciliary care, meaning that even if we
need to be hospitalized at home, the
insurance company will cover that cost
up to sum
and sure. In addition,
due to the protect benefit in this policy, the insurance company will
also cover non-payable items like PPE syringes
.  And
this policy also has a plus benefit,
meaning a bonus, so we are provided with a 50% bonus every year
.  And up to
100%, so if I take a 10 lock cover,
after two renewals my overall cover
amount will be 20 locks.  In addition,
we also have a restoration benefit.  So by
default, the
restoration benefit will work for us once.
However, if we take a rider, we will
also get the unlimited times restoration option.  And in this plan, we can
also include four adults
.  For example, if you want to include
your spouse and parents along with yourself,
you
can definitely consider this policy.  But if
we look at the drawbacks of this policy, the
premiums are comparatively a bit
higher.  And if there are waiting periods for
those with pre-existing conditions,
we are not
given the option to reduce them.  Now
coming to the second plan, Care Supreme.
This is arguably the most customizable plan
.  This means you are being
provided with better flexibility.   To
include the features you like
.  So what are the highlight features for us in this policy? By
default,
unlimited restoration is provided
.  So every time we make a claim,
our cover amount is refilled for us
.  For example, suppose I have
taken a cover amount of 10 lakhs
and
even if I have to be hospitalized five times in a year, they will provide me with a cover amount of 10 lakhs every time
through this benefit. So if we
take this add-on, just
like Optima Secure, they are providing us with a 50% bonus every year
up to 100%, but there
is a small twist in this policy.  The same is the
cumulative bonus super so this is an add-
on. With this add-on, we get an additional 100% bonus,
but they provide up to 500% so
overall if I take a 10 lock cover amount, by
default the bonus I get is
another additional 10 locks. In addition, the
bonus I get with this add-on is an additional
50 locks, so my 10 lock coverage
becomes 70 locks. If there are no after-fire renewals,
this add-on can sometimes be
mandatory for us. Based on our age
and location, if we
select the Care Supreme plan, we will have to take
this add-on
.  Now coming to the
basic features, we do
n't have any restrictions in this policy either.  There are no restrictions such as room
rent caps, copay payments
, or disease-wise sub-limits
.  And
even basic features are covered.
Coverages like AYUSH benefits, domiciliary coverage, and day care treatments are
all being provided up to some
extent.  And this policy, as I
said earlier, is one of the most
flexible plans, meaning it provides us with many
add-ons.
For example, with the add-ons in this policy,
we are providing coverage for pre-existing medical
conditions like diabetes, blood
pressure, cholesterol, asthma, etc.
from as early as 30 days without the need to serve a three-year waiting period
.  In addition,
we also have the chance to reduce the waiting period for other pre-existing conditions
from three years to one year or two years
.  Now coming to the
drawbacks.  As mentioned earlier, there is a
comparatively high volume
of complaints for care.  When you
compare it with HDFC or Aditya Birla
now coming to the next plan ad the
Birla Active 1Max it is a comparatively recently
launched product but
if you look at the specifications it is on par with
Optima Secure and Care Supreme
but provides features.
Especially in this policy, we are being
provided with a bonus of up to 500% if we default
.  So every year I get a 100%
bonus.  So after-fire
renewals would be a 500% bonus for me
.  This means that
after the fire renewals where I took a cover amount of 10 locks, my
overall coverage will be 60 locks.  Another unique
feature of this policy is health
returns.  So, by tracking how many steps we
take daily and how many calories we
burn,
we are given some cash back at the end of the year
.  So this cashback
can be up to 100%.  So
we have a super reload feature in this policy.  So
this is an unlimited restoration feature but
I can claim a combination of my base cover amount and the restoration
benefit
.  So this is a unique feature.  So
apart from this, we don't have any restrictions
.  So for example, there are no restrictions like room
rent restrictions, co-payments or
disease-related supplements,
and even in this policy,
we are provided with many benefits
.  Specifically, to reduce the waiting period for our pre-
existing medical conditions, we are
providing coverage from day one for the seven listed medical conditions, as well as for medical conditions like diabetes, blood pressure, asthma, and even angioplasty
.  If we
take out the chronic care add-on and for other medical
conditions, we also have the option to reduce the three-year waiting
period to one or two years
.  So
what are the drawbacks? The company is
relatively new.  So, health
insurance operations
started in 2016.  So long-term claims data is
not available.  Coming to the
summary of these three plans HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure.  If you want the best
customer support, day one double coverage and
strong brand value, then
you should definitely consider
HDFC Argo Optima Secure. If you
want the best flexibility, innovative features and better
bonus options, then
you can consider Care Supreme and finally, if you want coverage for some serious pre-existing conditions as well and want great restoration benefits, good bonuses and overall good features, then you can also consider Aditya Berla Active One
.  So, you can select the best plan among these three plans
based on your age, health profile, and budget
.
If you are still confused, don't worry, just
book a free call with Tito and our
insurance experts will explain
these policies to you in detail in simple Telugu
.  And besides, they will
also recommend the perfect policy that suits you by comparing these policies
.  So the link description
will be no spam, no pressure, just
honest guidance.  So if you liked this video,
please like and share
and for more in-depth videos like this
and policy reviews, please
subscribe to Dito Insurance Telugu. Let's
meet again in the next video with another interesting plan.  Till then stay
healthy stay informed about the signing of
Ajith from Ditto